Guide to the Photographs of Asian Americans
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Photographs of Asian Americans.
1930-1982
WA Photos 485
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.29
(2 boxes)
Photographs of Asian Americans created by Asian American photographers and others, chiefly in California, circa 1930-1982.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources. For more information see notes associated with each photograph.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
This collection has no permanent box or folder designations for items within it, so patrons should note the photographer and image description when requesting materials
Scope and Contents
Photographs of Asian Americans created by Asian American photographers and others, chiefly in California, circa 1930-1982.
Portraiture in the collection includes wedding portraits and graduation portraits, as well as studio portraits of families and individuals. Identified sites of images include a group in front of the Soto Zen Mission of the Sokoji Buddhist Church in San Francisco, California, and a group portrait of attendees of the Western Federation of Buddhist Sunday School Teachers League Conference in front of the Lodi Buddhist Church in Lodi, California, in January 1957.
Photographers represented in the collection include Eschol Manning Hammond, Paul Henry Hammond, Miyowa (George) Hishida, Sadaichi Imada, Morinosuke (Jack) Kamikihara, Charles Fred Kohler, and Richard S. Yoshikawa.
Photographic studios represented in the collection include Barboni Studio, George Studio, Hammond Studio, Imada Studio, Kami Studio, Salon Studio, Sandino Studio, Tru-Lite Studio, Wee Picture Studio, and Yoshikawa Studio.
Image descriptions of the photographic prints are derived from inscriptions on the verso and recto of the item and from image analysis by the archivist. Descriptions usually include information about the working locations of the photographer or studio, and occasionally physical characteristics of items, such as image numbers applied by the photographers or inscriptions by previous owners, as well as contextual information about the images.
Each folder contains a single photographic print.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Photographs, circa 1930-circa 1965. II. Oversize Photographs, circa 1930-1982.
Asian Americans -- Pictorial works; Buddhism -- California; Photographers -- West (U.S.); San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; California -- Pictorial works; Lodi (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Photographic prints; Hammond, Eschol Manning, 1890-1952; Hammond, Paul Henry, 1895-1950; Hishida, Miyowa, 1896-1992; Imada, Sadaichi, 1885-1952; Kamikihara, Morinosuke, 1904-1988; Kohler, Charles Fred, 1874-1957; Yoshikawa, Richard S., 1920-2011; Barboni Studio (San Francisco, Calif.); George Studio (Fresno, Calif.); Hammond Studio (Porterville, Calif.); Imada Studio (Los Angeles, Calif.); Kami Studio (San Francisco, Calif.); Lodi Buddhist Church (Lodi, Calif.); Salon Studio (San Francisco, Calif.); Sandino Studio (San Francisco, Calif.); Sōtōshū; Tru-Lite Studio (San Francisco, Calif.); Wee Picture Studio (San Francisco, Calif.)
- Photographs, circa 1930-circa 1965; Series I; (14 photographic prints)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by the surname of the photographer or the corporate name of the studio.
  Scope and Contents
  This subseries consists of vintage photographic prints with dimensions less than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.). Photographic materials with dimensions larger than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.) are located in the Oversize Photographs series.
  - Barboni Studio
    Biographical/Historical note
    Barboni Studio was a photography studio in Oakland and San Francisco, California
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American woman wearing a mortar board and gown, circa 1939 (Box 1)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Purchased from Bolerium Books on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2011
  - George Studio
    Photography studio of Japanese American photographer Miyowa (George) Hishida (1896-1992) in Fresno, California
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American man, circa 1930 (Box 1)
      Photographic print housed in a cardboard mat folder with letterpress impression identifying the studio on the recto interior of the folder
  - Hishida, Miyowa (George)
    Related Archival Materials note
    Associated materials: See: George Studio
  - Imada, Sadaichi
    Associated materials: See: Imada Studio
  - Imada Studio
    Photography studio of Japanese American photographer Sadaichi Imada (1885-1952) at 239 1/2 East First Street, Los Angeles, California
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American woman wearing a mortar board and gown, circa 1930-1935 (Box 1)
      Photographic print housed in a cardboard mat folder with a letterpress impression identifying the studio on the recto interior of the folder
  - Kami Studio
    Associated materials: See also: Series II. Oversize Photographs
    Photography studio of Japanese American photographer Morinosuke (Jack) Kamikihara (1904-1988) in San Francisco, California
    - Group portrait of eight Japanese American women and sixteen men, including a priest, on the steps of the Soto Zen Mission of the Sokoji Buddhist Church at 1881 Bush Street, San Francisco, circa 1950 (Box 1)
    - Group portrait of approximately one hundred Japanese American children, women, and men posed sitting and standing in a gymnasium, circa 1950 (Box 1)
  - Kamikihara, Morinosuke (Jack)
    Associated materials: See: Kami Studio
  - Kohler, Charles Fred
    Charles Fred Kohler (1874-1957) operated a photography studio in Los Angeles, California
    - Studio portrait of two Asian American men, identified as Liang Xin Fang and his father, 1943 (Box 1)
      Photographic print housed in a cardboard mat folder with an ink stamp identifying the photographer on the recto interior of the folder
      Ink inscription in Chinese on the interior of the mat folder, "Fang, Liang Xin, and his father, for Zhou, Cheng Fang, 1943"
  - Sandino Studio
    Photography studio located at 1317 Stockton Street, San Francisco, California
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American man wearing a mortar board and gown, identified as Warren Lowe, circa 1955-1960 (Box 1)
  - Tru-Lite Studio
    Photography studio located at 862 Clay Street, San Francisco, California
    - Studio portraits of two Asian American men and an Asian American woman, circa 1965 (Box 1)
      Two photographic prints housed in a cardboard mat folder with letterpress impressions identifying the studio on the recto interiors of the folders
  - Wee Picture Studio
    Photography studio located on Old Chinatown Lane, San Francisco, California
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American man and an Asian American woman, circa 1935-1940 (Box 1)
      Hand-tinted photographic print housed in a cardboard mat folder with an ink stamp identifying the studio on the recto interior of the folder
  - Unidentified photographers
    Photographs by discrete unidentified photographers
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American bride and groom, as well as an Asian American bridesmaid and groomsman, circa 1935-1940 (Box 1)
    - Informal group portrait of eleven couples of Asian American men and women, circa 1935-1940 (Box 1)
    - Studio portrait of a Chinese American woman wearing a mortar board and gown, identified as Mary Mae Cheong, 1939 (Box 1)
      Photographic print housed in a cardboard mat folder with an indistinct ink stamp identifying the studio, possibly Nu-Art Studio, on the recto interior of the folder, as well as an inscription in ink to Mrs. Lee from Cheong.
      Mary Mae Cheong (born circa 1921) graduate from Lowell High School in San Francisco in 1939 and from the University of California at Berkeley in 1944
    - Interior group portrait of nine Asian American men and an Asian American woman posed standing behind a casket, probably in a funeral parlor; one man wears regalia that designates him as a Buddhist clergyman, circa 1940-1950 (Box 1)
    - Informal interior portrait of two Japanese American men; they wear hats that identify their membership in Townsend Harris Post No. 438 of the American Legion in San Francisco, California, circa 1950 (Box 1)
- Oversize Photographs, circa 1930-1982; Series II; (7 photographic prints)
  This subseries consists of vintage photographic prints with dimensions greater than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.).
  - Hammond Studio
    Photography studio operated by Eschol Manning Hammond (1890-1952) and Paul Henry Hammond (1895-1950) in Porterville, California
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American family consisting of three girls, three boys, mother, and father, circa 1930 (Box 2)
  - Kami Studio
    Associated materials: See also: Series I. Photographs
    - Studio portrait of a Japanese American woman, circa 1950 (Box 2)
  - Salon Studio
    Photography studio in San Francisco, California
    - Group portrait of Chinese American attendees of the Hoy Sun Ning Yung Benevolent Association National Convention in San Francisco, California, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Yoshikawa Studio
    Photography studio of Japanese American photographer Richard S. Yoshikawa (1920-2011) in Stockton, California
    - Group portrait of Asian American attendees of the Western Federation of Buddhist Sunday School Teachers League Conference in front of the Lodi Buddhist Church in Lodi, California, 1957 January 27 (Box 2)
      Persons in the group hold signs for different districts
  - Unidentified photographers
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American woman and Asian American man, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
      Photographic print housed in a cardboard mat folder
    - Studio portrait of an Asian American family consisting of four girls, four boys, mother, and father, circa 1940-circa 1950 (Box 2)
    - Group portrait of an Asian American bride and groom, as well as an Asian American flower girl, three Asian American bridesmaids, and four Asian American groomsmen, circa 1950 (Box 2)